Minutes of the Executive Council of AFL, Pt. 2 on Microfilm 5918 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Minutes 1944-1945 (Reel 12)
  - 0881. Meeting Minutes of October 15-124, 1945. 100 pages., 8 (Reel 12)
    Major Topics: Anglo-American Trade Union Committee; anti- labor legislation in Massachusetts; British Trades Union Congress; Hollywood studio unions jurisdiction dispute between Carpenters, Painters, and Theatrical Stage Employees; withdrawal of Montreal, Canada, Trades and Labor Council; jurisdiction controversy between Operating Engineers and Firemen and Oilers in Louisville, Kentucky, strike; Farmers Cooperative meeting with American Federation of Labor; American Federation of Labor foreign policy statement; Ladies Handbag and Novelty Workers jurisdiction dispute; Mexican immigration; Government Employees Council formed; housing legislation; American Federation of Labor statements of housing, taxes, wages, and wage and price controls; Teamsters protest National Labor Relations Board ruling on California Cannery Workers jurisdiction to Congress of Industrial Organizations; World Trade Union Congress; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
- Minutes 1945-1957 (Reel 13)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of October 15-24, 1945 (continued). 62 pages., 1 (Reel 13)
    Major Topics: Anglo-American Trade Union Committee; British Trades Union Congress; jurisdiction controversy between Operating Engineers and Firemen and Oilers in Louisville, Kentucky, hotel strike; Farmers Cooperative meeting with American Federation of Labor; Ladies Handbag and Novelty Workers jurisdiction dispute; Labor-Management Conference; League for Human Rights; jurisdiction controversy in Hollywood studios between Painters, Carpenters, and Theatrical Stage Employees; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0063. Meeting Minutes of January 21-31, 1946. 202 pages., 2 (Reel 13)
    Major Topics: United Nations; Air Force adequacy; Brewery and Soft Drink Workers re-affiliation; Hollywood studios strike and jurisdiction dispute among Operating Engineers, Carpenters, and Theatrical Stage Employees; federal labor legislation; Cuban labor situation; federal aid to education; jurisdiction dispute between Operating Engineers and Firemen and Oilers in Louisville, Kentucky, hotels; conditions in Germany; housing shortage; inflation and price controls; Latin American labor movement; anti-labor law in Florida; John L. Lewis elected vice president; Machinists jurisdiction controversies; Progressive Mine Workers of America oppose United Mine Workers re-affiliation; Japan and Philippines organization of labor unions; postwar reconversion of employment policies; American Federation of Labor resolution on Spain; State, County, and Municipal Employees competition with Congress of Industrial Organizations; American Federation of Labor statements on federal labor legislation; housing in Germany; inflation; postwar reconversion; Spain and taxation; World Federation of Trade Unions; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; super-seniority litigation.
  - 0265. Meeting Minutes of May 15-22, 1946. 133 pages., 3 (Reel 13)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor Financial Committee Report; federal anti-labor legislation, Case bill; Automobile Workers loan refinance and jurisdiction competition with Machinists; Brewery and Soft Drink Workers re-affiliation; Carpenters protest decision in Hollywood studio jurisdiction dispute; Teamsters activities in California; Cannery Workers on Pacific Coast protest National Labor Relations Board ruling; Communist activities in southern California; trade unions in Germany; Government Employees Council; United Mine Workers Health and Welfare Fund; Building Service Employees dispute with Hod Carriers and Laborers in Hollywood Studio jurisdiction; United States Senate investigation of industrial unrest; Latin American labor movements; Maritime Trades Council; Machinists affiliation status; Maritime Trades Council proposed; southern states organizing campaign; Pan American Labor Movement; union label application to grain products; Wisconsin State Federation of Labor competition with Congress of Industrial Organizations; American Federation of Labor membership statistics.
  - 0398. Meeting Minutes of August 12-20, 1946. 184 pages., 4 (Reel 13)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor Financial Committee Report; Hollywood studios jurisdiction settlement; Cannery Workers in California; Commercial Telegraphers jurisdiction extension and dispute with Communications Workers; Operating Engineers dispute with Machinists policies for Central Labor Unions and State Federations of Labor; federal aid to education; housing legislation; formation of Maritime Trades Council; Machinists dissociation from American Federation of Labor; National Farm Labor Union jurisdiction request; price controls; farmers cooperatives; Auto Workers jurisdiction over Farm Implement Manufacturers; labor conditions in Germany; American Federation of Labor housing program; International Labor Organization; Musicians Union opposition to Lea Bill amending Federal Communications Act; Minneapolis Central Labor Union and Congress of Industrial Organizations; Memphis Central Labor Union and Teamsters Union; southern states organizing campaign; United Textile Workers of America; American Federation of Labor membership statistics.
  - 0582. Meeting Minutes of October 6 and 18, 1946. 40 pages., 5 (Reel 13)
    Major Topics: Alaska organizing efforts among Seafarers and Mine Workers; right-to-work legislation in Nebraska; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress; southern organizing campaign; Germany; Hollywood studios jurisdiction controversy; American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees jurisdiction extensions to nurses; reinstatement of Railroad Signalmen; Railroad Brotherhoods; United Nations.
  - 0622. Meeting Minutes of January 29-February 5, 1947. 145 pages., 6 (Reel 13)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity negotiations; Watch Workers Union charter application; anti-labor legislation; American Federation of Labor mission to Argentina; Metal Trades unions complaints about Automobile Workers Union; British Trades Union Congress; International Labor Office; agricultural workers wage ceiling; Firemen and Oilers merger negotiations with Operating Engineers; Auto Workers jurisdiction request over Farm Implement Workers; American Federation of Labor mission to Germany; American Federation of Labor Housing Committee report; Hollywood studio jurisdiction dispute between Carpenters and Theatrical and Stage Employees; American Federation of Labor jurisdiction policies in amusement industry; Moscow Peace Conference; salaries of American Federation of Labor organizers; slave labor; southern organizing campaign; American Federation of Labor resolution on Spain; American Federation of Labor statement on universal military training; right-to-work law in Nebraska; United Nations Security Council; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0767. Meeting Minutes of April 21-25, 1947. 104 pages., 7 (Reel 13)
    Major Topics: Anti-labor legislation (Taft-Hartley Bill); Hollywood studio unions jurisdiction dispute; Metal Trades dispute with Automobile Workers; Firemen and Oiler merger with Operating Engineers; Carpenters dispute with Theatrical Stage Employees in Hollywood; Latin American labor movement; Machinists re-affiliation; southern organizing campaign; American Federation of Labor financial report and membership statistics.
  - 0871. Meeting Minutes of September 8-13, 1947. 141 pages., 8 (Reel 13)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity negotiations; American Federation of Labor policy against collaboration with Congress of Industrial Organizations; anti-labor legislation (Taft-Hartley Act); Canadian labor movement; Carpenters dispute with Theatrical Stage Employees over Hollywood jurisdiction; British Trades Union Congress; Germany conditions; inflation and price controls; report on Japan; non-communist affidavits; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters dispute with Railway shop Craft Unions; Railroad Brotherhoods opposition to Taft-Hartley legislation; United Nations children's aid; women's commission.
- Minutes 1948-1950 (Reel 14)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of January 26-February 3, 1948. 165 pages., 1 (Reel 14)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor cooperation with Congress of Industrial Organizations against Taft-Hartley; American Federation of Labor litigation; Carpenters dispute with Upholsterers; anti-communism; southern organizing campaign; slave labor; American Heritage Foundation; Hollywood jurisdiction controversy; inflation and price control; jurisdiction dispute machinery; Labor's League for Political Education; American Federation of Labor-sponsored labor-management legislation; Latin American Confederation of Labor; equal pay of women; Fair Employment Practices bill; Marshall Plan; Minneapolis Central Labor Union collaboration with Congress of Industrial Organizations; National Farm Labor Union; contract with American Federation of Labor counsel Joseph Padway; Sleeping Car Porters dispute with Railroad Shop Craft Unions; migrant labor; Taft-Hartley Act; universal military training; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0166. Meeting Minutes of May 10-14, 1948. 132 pages., 2 (Reel 14)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor consultants to United Nations; Building and Construction Trades Department dispute with Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers; Carpenters dispute with Upholsterers Union; Chinese Federation of Labor; Department of Federal Labor Unions proposed; American Federation of Labor representation in European Recovery (Marshall) Plan; Grain Millers petition for charter; Jewelry Workers protest charter to Watch Workers; Inter-American Confederation of Labor; American Federation of Labor litigation; labor planks in political party platforms; Progressive Mine Workers of America; Sleeping Car Porters dispute with Railway Shop Crafts; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; American Federation of Labor International Labor Relations Department Report.
  - 0298. Meeting Minutes of August 23-27, 1948. 105 pages., 3 (Reel 14)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor nonpartisan political policy in 1948 elections; Building and Construction Trades Department jurisdiction problems; Carpenters dispute with Upholsterers; Chemical Workers jurisdiction problems; American Federation of Labor representation on Marshall Plan; Defense Fund to defend unions against anti-labor laws; American Federation of Labor activities in Hawaii; Machinists dispute with Teamsters and Retail Clerks in strike at Boeing Corporation, Seattle; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0403. Meeting Minutes of November 13-15, 19, and 23, 1948. 59 pages., 4 (Reel 14)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor attitude toward Taft-Hartley Act; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress dispute with Railway Clerks; Cigar Makers merger with Tobacco Workers; American Federation of Labor organizing in Hawaii; Labor's League for Political Education; Seafarers International Union organizing on west coast; Carpenters dispute with Upholsterers Union; American Federation of Labor legislative agenda.
  - 0462. Meeting Minutes of January 31-February 8, 1949. 167 pages., 5 (Reel 14)
    Major Topics: Amendments to National Labor Act; housing; World Federation of Trade Unions; American Federation of Labor statement on social justice; international affairs; Panama; repeal of Taft-Hartley Act; Building and Construction Trades Department jurisdiction matters; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress relations with American Federation of Labor; Bridge and Structural Iron Workers jurisdiction matters; Carpenters dispute with Upholsterers; Congress of Industrial Organizations proposal for conference with American Federation of Labor and Railroad Brotherhoods; Communications Workers of America possible affiliation discussed; federal aid to education; labor in Hawaii; Hotel and Restaurant Employees Union organization in Miami, Florida; American Federation of Labor legislation agenda; Thomas amendments to National Labor Act; equal pay for women; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0629. Meeting Minutes of May 16-20, 1949. 174 pages., 6 (Reel 14)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity report; Air Line Pilots Association charter protested by Flight Engineers; Aluminum Workers charter application; United States foreign policy toward China; Bridge and Structural Iron Workers jurisdiction matters; Building and Construction trades Department jurisdiction matters; Carpenters dispute with Upholstery Workers; American Federation of Labor organization in Alaska; policies toward Federal Labor Unions; rent control; Workers Education Bureau; Hawaiian labor situation report; American Federation of Labor litigation report; repeal of Taft-Hartley Act; National Security Program; American Federation of Labor organization campaign; social security; Textile Workers of America jurisdiction matters; American Federation of Labor consultants to United Nations; World Federation of Free Democratic Unions; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0803. Meeting Minutes of August 15-19, 1949. 136 pages., 7 (Reel 14)
    Major Topics: Aluminum Workers charter application; Bridge and Structural Iron Workers jurisdiction matters; Building and Construction Trades Department jurisdiction matters; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress suspension of Seamen's Union; federal aid to education; Federal Labor Unions, strike benefits; labor situation in Hawaii; American Federation of Labor legislative program; Machinists re- affiliation with American Federation of Labor; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People request for financial assistance; Seafarers International Union charter application; Marine Engineers charter application; Textile Workers of America jurisdiction matters; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0939. Meeting Minutes of October 2, 5, and 11, 1949. 46 pages., 8 (Reel 14)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations noncooperation in political matters; Building and Construction Trades Department jurisdiction matters; Carpenters dispute with Upholsterers; age discrimination; government employees; Hawaii organizing drive; Israel labor movement; Labor's League for Political Education; Maintenance of Way Employees jurisdiction matters.
  - 0985. Meeting Minutes of January 30-February 7, 1950. 105 pages., 9 (Reel 14)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity; American Federation of Labor financial obligations to International Confederation of Free Trade Unions; displaced persons; Grain Millers dispute with Building and Construction Trades Department; housing; American Federation of Labor litigation report; Machinists re-affiliation negotiations; national defense; American Federation of Labor position on Point-Four Program; American Federation of Labor statement on genocide; public housing; repeal of Taft-Hartley Act; social security legislation; State, County, and Municipal Employees.
- Minutes 1950-1952 (Reel 15)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of January 30-February 7, 1950 (continued). 25 pages., 1 (Reel 15)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; report of American Federation of Labor Committee on Social Security.
  - 0026. Meeting Minutes of May 8-11, 1950. 108 pages., 2 (Reel 15)
    Major Topics: Building and Construction Trades Department complaint about raiding by United Mine Workers District 50; Carpenters-Upholsterers; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations political cooperation; American Federation of Labor litigation; Machinists re-affiliation with American Federation of Labor; State, County, and Municipal Employees in Pennsylvania and Montana; American Federation of Labor study on pension and welfare funds; fair labor standards in Puerto Rico; National Labor Relations Board reorganization; age discrimination; United States foreign policy; Federal Labor Union strike benefits; sugar Act of 1948; Swedish labor movement, invitation to American Federation of Labor delegation; white collar workers; Workers Education Bureau; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0134. Meeting Minutes of August 8-11, 1950. 84 pages., 3 (Reel 15)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity committee and political cooperation; Building and Construction Trades Department jurisdiction dispute with Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employees; national wage and price controls and rationing; Machinists re-affiliation; State, County, and Municipal Employees Union in Montana; printing trades unions dispute with Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers; Schumann Plan for joint French-German control of steel and coal; Workers Education Bureau; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0218. Meeting Minutes of September 17 and 24, 1950. 19 pages., 4 (Reel 15)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organization unity negotiations; Arizona State Federation of Labor on Central Arizona Project; British Trades Union Congress; social security legislation.
  - 0237. Meeting Minutes of January 22-29, 1951. 116 pages., 5 (Reel 15)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity negotiations; Florida citrus workers strike; New York State Defense Emergency Act; Hawaiian labor movement; Labor's League for Political Education; National Security Training Act of 1950; American Federation of Labor organizing activities; American Federation of Labor message to Russian people; Saint Lawrence Seaway Project; American Federation of Labor policy on strike benefits; amendments to Taft-Hartley Act; universal military training; Virginia right to work legislation; International Ladies Garment Workers Union dispute with New York Central Labor Union; American Federation of Labor litigation.
  - 0353. Meeting Minutes of May 14-18, 1951. 132 pages., 6 (Reel 15)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor legislative program; report on American Federation of Labor finances; American Federation of Labor litigation; baseball players organization; Blacksmiths amalgamation with Boilermakers; Building and Construction trades Department jurisdiction dispute with Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employees; National Farm Labor Union; Defense Housing Program; International Confederation of Free Trade Unions; Leather Workers amalgamation with Butcher Workmen; Machinists jurisdiction dispute and raiding charges; wartime economic controls, wages, prices, and rationing; Saint Lawrence Seaway Project; amendments to Taft-Hartley Act; Veterans Preference Act; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0485. Meeting Minutes of August 7-10, 1951. 79 pages., 7 (Reel 15)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor withdrawal from unity negotiations with Congress of Industrial Organizations; American Federation of Labor finances studied; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress; agricultural organizations hostility toward organized labor; Building and Construction Trades Department dispute with Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employees; National Farm Labor Union organization of dairy farmers; Soviet aggression in Europe; International Labor Organization; Federal Labor Unions strike benefits; International Confederation of Free Trade Unions; Spanish fascism; National Labor Relations Board unfavorable decisions on Taft-Hartley; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0564. Meeting Minutes of September 16, 23, and 25, 1951. 19 pages., 8 (Reel 15)
    Major Topics: Textile Workers jurisdiction dispute with Hosiery Workers; non-Communist affidavits signed by Executive Council members; United Labor Policy Committee.
  - 0583. Meeting Minutes of January 28-February 5, 1952. 146 pages., 9 (Reel 15)
    Major Topics: Inflation; colonial undeveloped countries; Japan; American Federation of Labor litigation; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity negotiations; Australian Council of Trade Unions; Building and Construction Trades Department dispute with Maintenance of Way Employees; Compulsory Military Training legislation; Communist-dominated labor unions; National Farm Labor Union; International Confederation of Free Trade Unions; American Federation of Labor endorsement of Israeli bonds; Japanese Peace Treaty; Korea; National Labor Relations Board cases involving Machinists and Carpenters; American Federation of Labor cooperation with Mexican labor movement; mining disasters legislation; moral rearmament; American Federation of Labor organizing program; Longshoremen dispute with Teamsters and Printing Pressmen; racial violence in Florida; social security; subversive activities; Taft-Hartley repeal efforts; wage stabilization; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; federal tax policy.
  - 0729. Meeting Minutes of May 19-22, 1952. 137 pages., 10 (Reel 15)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor legislative agenda; anti-labor bills; wage and price controls; displaced persons legislation; amendments to National Labor Relations Act; Saint Lawrence Seaway Project; National Agricultural Workers Union; Building and Construction Trades Department jurisdiction disputes; National Labor Relations Board cases involving Carpenters and Machinists; wage and price controls; National Council of Government Employees; International Confederation of free Trade Unions; American Federation of Labor report on immigration and naturalization; National Defense Program; Taft-Hartley amendments; social security benefit liberalization; moral rearmament; Puerto Rican constitution and labor movement; racketeering in labor unions; American Federation of Labor finances and membership; Teamsters jurisdiction disputes with Plumbers and Printing Pressmen; Texas State Federation of Labor; Ohio State Federation of Labor on labor unity; Federal Wage Stabilization Board.
  - 0866. Meeting Minutes of August 11-15, 1952. 93 pages., 11 (Reel 15)
    Major Topics: United Automobile Workers of America; building and Construction Trades Department report; Carpenters dispute with Machinists; inflation and cost of living; GI Bill of Rights for Veterans of Korean War; Native Americans employment; Jewelry Workers charter controversy; racketeering among New York Longshoremen; American Federation of Labor organizing program in Michigan; political party conventions; Puerto Rico labor movement; women's auxiliaries; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0959. Meeting Minutes of September 14, 22, and 24, 1952. 46 pages., 12 (Reel 15)
    Major Topics: Building and Construction Trades Department jurisdiction dispute with Chemical Workers; presidential endorsements by American Federation of Labor; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity proposal by John L. Lewis; Justice Department ruling on television producers rights to motion picture productions; Puerto Rico labor movement; non-communist affidavits signed by American Federation of Labor Executive Council in compliance with Taft-Hartley Act; television; Textile Workers of America financial investigation.